Location: /nfs/public/rw/es/projects/biocatalogue/test/config/initializers/biocat_local.rb

# BioCatalogue: app/config/initializers/biocat_local.rb.pre
#
# Copyright © 2008, University of Manchester, The European Bioinformatics
# Institute (EMBL-EBI) and the University of Southampton.
# See license.txt for details

# Private settings that apply to individual deployments.

# This setting determines where trashing (via the acts_as_trashable plugin) is used.
ENABLE_TRASHING = true

# This setting determines whether search indexing is enabled or not.
ENABLE_SEARCH = true

# Show the debug box at the end of the page or not.
SHOW_DEBUG = false

# Switch event logging on or off.
USE_EVENT_LOG = true

# Set a proxy for open-uri calls
#If :proxy option is specified, the value should be String,
#URI, boolean or nil. When String or URI is given,
#it is treated as proxy URI.
#When true is given or the option itself is not specified,
#environment variable `scheme_proxy’ is examined. `scheme’
#is replaced by `http’, `https’ or `ftp’.
#When false or nil is given, the environment variables
#are ignored and connection will be made to a server directly.
HTTP_PROXY = 'http://www-proxy.ebi.ac.uk:3128'

PORT = '8990'

# Enable or disable endpoint status check icon in view
ENABLE_STATUS_DISPLAY = true

# defaults to exception.notifier@default.com
ExceptionNotifier.sender_address = %(“BioCatalogue Errors” contact@biocatalogue.org)

# defaults to ”[ERROR] “
#ExceptionNotifier.email_prefix = ”[APP-#{RAILS_ENV.capitalize} ERROR] “

# defaults to false - meaning by default it sends email. Setting true will cause it to only render the error pages, and NOT email.
# For local development purposes this SHOULD be set to true.
ExceptionNotifier.render_only = false

ExceptionNotifier.exception_recipients = %w(contact@biocatalogue.org)

# ==============================================================

# Enable or disable the cache-money plugin, which caches AR models in memcached.
# This setting may be useful in instances when cache-money is not working as required/
ENABLE_CACHE_MONEY = false

# The sender email address for emails sent from the application.
SENDER_EMAIL_ADDRESS = “contact@biocatalogue.org”

# The email address used for sending feedback from users to.
FEEDBACK_EMAIL_ADDRESS = “contact@biocatalogue.org”

# reCAPTCHA settings:
ENV[“RECAPTCHA_PUBLIC_KEY”] = “6Lff_QYAAAAAABdXktnhabbQguELRw5r6q2xaDTr”
ENV[“RECAPTCHA_PRIVATE_KEY”] = “6Lff_QYAAAAAANDXFRd76iB8jDd0DTxZEhd7Bvin”

# The site's base host URL (for times when the base host cannot be obtained from controllers):
SITE_BASE_HOST = “http://test.biocatalogue.org“

# Twitter integration:
ENABLE_TWITTER = false
TWITTER_ACCOUNT_URL = “http://twitter.com/biocat_test“
TWITTER_ACCOUNT_EMAIL = “biocatalogue-developers@rubyforge.org”;
TWITTER_ACCOUNT_PASSWORD = “biocateatdogs”

# Addthis.com bookmarking widget integration:
ENABLE_BOOKMARKING_WIDGET = true
ADDTHIS_USERNAME = “biocatalogue”

# Google Analytics:
ENABLE_GOOGLE_ANALYTICS = false
GOOGLE_ANALYTICS_TRACKER_ID = 'xyz'

# WSDLUtils base URI
# E.g. WSDLUTILS_BASE_URI = 'http://localhost/WSDLUtils/WSDLUtils.php'
WSDLUTILS_BASE_URI = 'http://test.biocatalogue.org/WSDLUtils/WSDLUtils.php'

# ====================================================
# Configure local settings for the RPX Single Sign-On
# (for OpenID, Twitter, Facebook, etc logins - see https://rpxnow.com/)
# —————————————————-

ENABLE_RPX = true
RPX_REALM = 'biocatalogue'
RPX_API_KEY = '5d662627dfdf36fb50444f8b0b6c09cf82bcb08b'

# ====================================================

# Setting to determine whether mappings (eg: “give me the relevant service provider that might be related to this annotation”)
# are carried out after getting the raw results from Solr.
# If set to true, this may cause search to be slower but has the best chance of returning all relevant results.
# If set to false, it is crucial that all relevant associated object IDs are indexed together with the items, in Solr.
SEARCH_PERFORM_POST_SOLR_MAPPINGS = false

# The message to display at the very top of the page.
# Use this for extra special messages like very important announcements and maintenance notices.
HEADER_MESSAGE = ”<span style='font-size:153.1%; font-weight:bold;'><b>PLEASE NOTE: This BioCatalogue instance is running under REE & VM.</b></span>“

# The list of email addresses that ALL status change emails should be sent to.
# This augments any other status change notification feature.
# This MUST be an array of email addresses or a blank array.
MONITORING_STATUS_CHANGE_RECIPIENTS = [“contact@biocatalogue.org” ]

# This setting determines whether notifications
# about service status should be sent to service
# submitters or anyone responsible for the service in
# addition to those included in the status recipients list above.
NOTIFY_SERVICE_RESPONSIBLE = false

# This setting determines whether SSL (via the ssl_requirement plugin) is used.
ENABLE_SSL = false

# For cases where an 'identifier' is not set for new annotation attributes,
# this config setting is be used as the default “catch all” template for generating
# an identifier.
ANNOTATION_ATTRIBUTE_DEFAULT_IDENTIFIER_TEMPLATE = “http://biocatalogue.org/attribute/%s“

F2F Pilot Development Review - 4th December 2008 @ EBI, Cambridge

Attending

Rodrigo, Dave, Carole, Jits, Thomas, Eric,

Notes by Dave

Broadly the Biocatalogue team is going to be very busy over the next 2 months getting code functionality and content in place, with a view to a code freeze in March and content bootstrapped for public release of the pilot service in April. What with Christmas, this is all only a few weeks away! Hence we're not looking at many interactions with myExperiment in the next few weeks, but there are many touch points thereafter.

- myExperiment may be able to help bootstrap the Biocatalogue content by providing services extracted from the growing body of workflows (mainly Taverna, but even perhaps Kepler on that timescale, and Trident if the services are in scope). It may also be able to provide some metadata for the services based on the workflow metadata.

- myExperiment would be able to provide, on an ongoing basis, some of the objective data that Biocatalogue uses to establish information about services that is then used to assist sorting and comparison during service discovery. For example, the number of workflows that use a service could contribute to a popularity measure. (This is one of many possible sources - there will be many services on Biocatalogue that are not used by workflows on myExperiment.)

- myExperiment will be able to query Biocatalogue for service status information. Steve Pettifer illustrated his traffic light system for services. MyExperiment and/or Taverna will also (in the fullness of time) be able to ask Biocatalogue for services that are similar to a given service.

- There was a lot of insightful discussion today about discovery. As myExperiment is gaining more content we have not yet developed the discovery interface further to cope with this. Some of the ideas in today's discussion are directly applicable to myExperiment - such as not thinking of ranking of search results as much as providing an interface for comparing a number of workflows.

- The annotation model that is being developed in Biocatalogue is a generic RoR 2 plugin which provides attribute-value pairs (together with an initial set of possible domain values for the value part). This is a generically reusable e-Lab component that we may be able to apply in the evolved myExperiment codebase. Jits is currently working on the UI. The data model was discussed at lenth and appears to sit comfortably with the future use of ontologies.

- The deployment architecture of Biocatalogue has followed similar principles to myExperiment but has two levels of redundancy (and hardware load-balancing). There is still work to be done on optimising the SOLR config. It would be very useful to compare notes at some stage.

- A number of lessons from myExperiment were fed into Biocatalogue today, including the need to track housekeeping and sysadmin data in order to generate stats, and some policy questions relating to content removal.

Thanks very much to our hosts at EBI for a really productive meeting.

Notes by Thomas

Progress overview

All working together better with F2F. 2 publications out already.

Met already with half of the people on advisory board (Biomoby, Embrace…)

Pbs:

web server (solved except SOLR)

manpower estimates → be more realistic

wiki & website management (content update & look and feel)

documentation not transparent (especially data model) → needs to be better for outside people

wiki needs to be separated in public and developper

needs UML/ER diagram for data model

review activities

timetable

Steve is officially part of the team → now part of myGrid family, helping on lot of stuff including management

Words from our users & Pals:

ranking: usefulness, stability…

testing & examples

Service profile:

conditions of use, e.g policy for using (no more than 200 requests/min…)

Submit:

some user would make an effort in providing meta-data if they could see that it'd boost them in the rankings

submit a test

submit a monitoring mechanism

need a feed telling submitter what is their ranking → need an automatic feedback to encourage people to go back to their service and annotate further

adding meta-data via email ?

need free text annotation (e.g description) as soon as possible

tags will also provide quick and very important infos to sort, ranks and find

manage competitiveness: do not discourage people if they've got low rankings. Need to encourage redundancy of services.

Search:

ranking: search & compare

filter

monitor

review

invoke: being able to invoke the service you found

Ownership & 3rd party submission ⇒ very important and very careful If you submit a service which is not yours, you don't want to receive failure emails (should be able to opt out), that's the providers problem. Responsibilities have to be clearly defined (provider, submitter, tagger…).

Current tasks:

Ranking: bleed key properties into the list

Should we create our own categories of services and force submitter to select one or more ?

Ranking different from comparing: ranking is easy, but comparing is harder

Needs to store queries to be able to do some performance tuning later.

Activity audit

Task audit

Content audit

How can we auto-seed the documentation/tags for services → need to do an annotation jamboree

Interface, architecture & functionality

Need to make the difference between documentation from WSDL and user's description

Be able to search on URLs (not working at the moment) → see with Franck & Mickael

On register page

delete the word “optional” after “Extra information”

add “instruction for use of services”

“add new description” → or “describe your service” or “describe the function of your service” (description presented to the user and indexed by search engine)

box: “are you the owner of the service ?”

ownership ⇒ careful to address the pb (who to contact? submitter != owner) (ownership claims, ownership confirmation, wikipedia type “I dispute this fact”)

What does google see ?

Annotation plug-in

will be able to annotate everything

annotations will be key-value pairs

seeds: pre-populated tag words for example. Where do we get the value set from ? Will probably do it later as it might get tricky to get the value set right.

Monitoring, Sorting, Filtering

by strong typing (db fields)

by combination of values (popularity…)

in 1st instance → strong typing, but which fields do we allow users to sort on ?

identify preferred fields

capability of displaying

subset can be pre-populated

Objective criteria

freshness (date created, date updated)

reliability (test suite success, service uptime)

cost

performance (result from scripts, e.g. returns result in minutes,hours,days,months…)

provider (provenance, certification, compliance to standards)

geotagging

conditions (existence of)

level of annotation (documentation)

is it available now (since we last checked with date time, ping this service now)

nb of workflows in myExperiment using a particular WS

Subjective criteria

popularity (rating, comments, measured by a feed, usage statistics)

scalability ?

How do we clean-up (e.g. major change name…) ? Use of data policy.

Separate testing script from examples:

core tests script by provider

examples by users

building a test suite later as part of the curation process

Would be nice to be able to run tests in a generic way (through workflow in my Experiment).

Next steps in the Pilot

Steve wrote a DAS parser (BioSapiens is DAS). Steve has a collaborator who wrote a WSDL quality validator.

DAS, REST, Generic (not from the 3 other types).

3 biggies still missing:

discovery (sorting, filtering)

monitoring

content scrapping (put content in)

partially register WS (put a few WS from a provider, and then tell them we did and ask to take ownership and complete registration) → we need a mechanism to change the ownership. Avoid misrepresentation. Low level checking of ownership by matching email address with url of WS.

somebody registering a WS but not the owner can only do a partial registration. Need to be the owner to register tests for example.

We need to take into account editing (owner, description), but restricted fields.

Versioning might be put on the backburner. EMBRACEregistry deal with it by spotting changes in WSDL, send email to owner with links in the email you can follow: “minor change, ignore it”, “major change, bring me to the page to edit documentation”.

Public Beta → April to coincide with the EMBRACE exit. (code freeze in March, big population activity during March)

no myExperiment integration

no smart ranking

usability stuff on web interface

negotiations with providers in March

start content acquisition NOW

7 weeks of development

Data Model (Eric's slides)

Annotation:

context (service…)

provenance

categories of annotations

provenance

operational

functional

social

Cloning VS versioning ? In the 1st phase, we should do cloning and later versioning. Different service deployments should be nested in the UI as they're the same version of the service.

Might not have full annotations for the operations.

Need a high quality of logging (usage statistics, activity…) → setup google analytics.

Usecase: user types “input protein sequence” → needs to return services taking protein sequence as input.

Discover Register Annotate Monitor Aob (DRAMA)

DRAMA is a procedure in place to functionally test the BioCatalogue features after every release. It has to be carried out on the BioCatalogue test site. Below are described the steps required. The aim is to automate the process using tools such as Molybdenum

Discovery

From the BioCatalogue home page search for ‘protein’

Click ‘Next page of results’

Click ‘Switch to detail view’

Search for ‘protein sequence’

Select ‘KEGG’ service

Click one of the service tag (e.g. enzyme)

Back to KEGG service using the back arrow

Click one of the similar service on the right (e.g DDBJ)

Back to KEGG

Select one of the Category of the KEGG service (e.g Motifs)

Combine different filter using the panel on the left (e.g member = franck, service type = soap)

In the search within box, search for ‘KEGG’.

Clear filter

Select ‘bioinformatics in the tag cloud

Select ‘Search by data’ search for the following example data: MSSRIARALALVVTLLHLTRLALSTCPAACHCPLEAPKCAPGVGLVRDGCGCCKVCAKQL

Register

Create an account

Sign in using Google, Yahoo, FaceBook

Submit a SOAP service (e.g. http://webservices.genouest.org/typedservices/Xref.wsdl); fill all the fields, no need to worry about the meanings

Register a REST Service

Add one new endpoint via the “REST Endpoints” tab and add a name to the REST endpoint.

Register a Soaplab service if possible

Annotate

Go back to the soap service you’ve registered

Annotate each of the components in the service overview (documentation url, description, contact etc…). Don’t worry about the meaning of the terms.

Add tags to the same service

Go to the operation tab and add annotation and tags to the operations and inputs/outputs

Go to the REST service you registered and annotate the REST endpoint you created.

Create two new REST endpoints (in one go) and annotate one of the REST endpoints entirely.

Add at least two “Input/Output Representations” to the remaining REST endpoint and annotate one REST representation.

Go back to the KEGG service

Add annotations to the service and operations/inputs/outputs

Add several categories to the KEGG service or the service you registered

Add an alternative name

Promote one the alternative name as service display name

Monitor

Disable a test script from a selected service

Check the outcome

Enable the test script again

Add a custom monitoring endpoint to a REST service

Check the outcome

Any Others

Favorite a service

Delete service

Delete a REST representation.

Edit the path of a REST endpoint.

Assign a group to a REST endpoint.

Edit a REST service's base URL.

Update a REST parameter, alternating between “optional” and “required” and pay attention to the template generated.

Edit a custom monitoring endpoint to a REST service